Ayan Mohamed, Frontend developer

LONDON, UNITED KINGDOM · 07931764657

PROFILE

I have a keen appreciation for design and bring a creative problem-solving approach to create beautiful applications, and experiences users love. A supportive and enthusiastic team player with a sharp eye for detail and a commitment to producing well written and documented code.

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Frontend Developer, Barclays

Nov 2014 - Present, London

Delivery of the digital safety quiz: Worked in collaboration with stakeholders across the Digital team to create an engaging application to support the Digisafe marketing campaign. The application was built using HTML, CSS and vanilla JS and content managed by Adobe Experience Manager(AEM).

Barclays Design Language (BDL): Worked in an Agile and collaborative environment to create straightforward and beautiful experiences for users by building a design system that ensures cohesive, consistent and accessible designs across Barclays's website. The project is tracked and managed by Jira. Confluence is used to house project documentation. The components in the system are created using Sass, HTML and vanilla ES6 Javascript.

Barclays Online Banking redesign: Liaised with remote development teams in India to consult on the development of responsive pages that align with the Barclays Design Language.

Boards (Project management tool): Built this internal tool to create a transparent and collaborative approach to preventing duplication of projects across the Digital banking team. I worked closely with multiple project owners to rapidly iterated through different design concepts and prototypes to finalise the product strategy and application architecture. I used Sketch to design the UI, Jest to test and MongoDB, Express, React, Redux and Node to build the application.

Junior Solution Manager, Barclays

Oct 2013 - Oct 2014, London

Liaised with product owners to manage the renewal of SSL certificates. Created content for Barclays using the FATWIRE content management system. Built an asset search tool to simplify the asset search experience of the FATWIRE content management system. I used HTML, CSS and vanilla Javascript to create this application.

EDUCATION

Web Development Apprenticeship, Apprenticeship

Oct 2013 – Oct 2014, London

Quintin Kynaston School, GCSEs

London

DETAILS

London, United Kingdom

07931764657

ayanmohamed65@gmail.com

SKILLS

HTML (HTML5, PUG, EJS, Jekyll)

CSS (CSS3, SASS, BEM)

Javascript (ES6, jQuery)

Bootstrap

React

Redux

Sketch

Git

Babel

Grunt / Gulp

Node (Express)

Unit testing (Mocha,

Chai, Jest)

TDD

Accessibility

Agile

Jira

Confluence